welcome back to APUSH in under 3 minutes
no time for intros let's get into it
topic 4.5 introduces the market
Revolution the time of which great
Innovation and mechanization Agriculture
and commerce occurred is largely called
and known as the market Revolution which
is just a little part of the larger
industrial revolution of the world
inventions like the textile Machinery
steam engines interchangeable parts the
Telegraph and agricultural inventions
made production methods of different
products so much faster and easier
causing entrepreneurs to make a lot of
goods and businesses causing people to
buy buy more goods and you get the idea
one thing to note about the market
Revolution is the difference in
evolution between the North and the
South the North became a place for all
Industries housing all types of
manufacturing and businesses the Advent
of the cotton genin caused the South to
farm cotton furiously making the South
grow up making mostly Farms having
slaves work at them and selling the
cotton from those farms for massive
amounts of money now of course the South
needed to sell these Goods to other
countries mostly but different
legislation and Judicial Systems Support
of development of roads and canals and
railroads caused America Amer Regional
markets and selling to grow this would
link the North and the South heavily but
it should still be noted that no matter
how much the north and south are
connected in this time period before the
Civil War these areas were different on
values and culture and could not coexist
peacefully with one another the market
Revolution would also have a massive
impact on society and culture as well
but that is a next video Problem on the
screen now are AP style questions for
this topic pause
now I'll put the answers on the screen
now
please follow my social medias and I
will see you in the next one